hello
and welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft we are on episode four now
and things are starting to get a little
bit crazy as you can see i'm on mumbo's
island and i'm just trying to make sure
that nothing goes wrong just doing a
little bit of gardening today
and i just wanted to stop
of course
i just wanted to stop by and do a little
bit of gardening not not make a mess
as you know every episode i like to come
and visit mumbo's base and see what's
going on normally there's not a lot
going on so i just say hello and that's
about it that's about as far as it goes
but i've actually
decided to come up with an idea
an idea that you guys have been asking
for
hoping for
and one that i would like to do myself
and that's the idea of joining forces
with mumbo now as you guys know i am the
new guy i'm the new guy on the block go
away
thank you i'm the new guy on the block
here and
the only person i really know
is mumbo that no particularly well and i
want to get to know everybody else well
as well but i am sort of gravitated
towards mumbo because i actually do know
him and we've done videos in the past
and we've met and we even filmed my cats
together that's a pretty weird list of
things to say about your friends yeah we
filmed my cats so i thought we would
propose a joined forces idea but i don't
want to just go up to mumbo and say
yo
let's join forces because that seems a
bit odd so i kind of want to create
a conference room where i pitch the idea
now loads of people already have little
groups that they sort of record with
and
i want to make one of my own apparently
there's the nho
there is
how do you
there he is he's afk as usual ow
i don't think i was supposed to be in
here maybe that was anti-green
technology going on so we're in mumbo's
base
not sure what he's up to
looks like he's smelting glass
oh my goodness i've been doing this
manually why don't i do these things why
don't i make these machines
this would be so quick i really i need
to learn from you this is exactly why i
want to propose the joint effort
of buildstone okay i want to propose the
offer of buildstone which is
a group
why isn't that going oh there we go
that's fun that is really fun i need one
of those
so i want to propose
the idea of buildstone a group of people
that are builders and redstoners and we
work together to get the job done
whatever that job may be and because
mumbo and i live so close together i was
thinking we could tie
our bases together in some way work
together on projects also work on
messing with each other as well as
everybody else i want to create a
conference room somewhere in between our
bases
and then i'll bring mumbo in
and ask him i'll propose it with a whole
logo and everything i'm going to design
the whole thing but there's actually
something that i need to do
and that's make my base i am outgrowing
my base faster than i can build
so what i need to do is start my
futuristic build and i now have all of
the resources i need to get started to
complete the project no way i don't have
nearly enough of what i need but i have
a pretty good amount of resources i've
got yeah i've basically got chests full
of the stuff that i'm going to be
needing the dyes the glass the
terracotta i need to go shopping for a
start i need to go and get my hands on
some shulker boxes and apparent
what
how have i got the tag
how have i got the tag how did i get
tagged
i haven't seen anybody and i it's bad
it's bad form
it's bad form to tag someone afk
unless
it wasn't the slime machine was it
i'm i'm confused let's go back and
inspect mumbo's machine because i have a
feeling
i have a
a sneaky feeling actually let's go the
long way shall we i have it what is that
what
what is that
i am getting distract there's too many
things going on
i have mysteriously got the tag i have a
feeling mumbo's machine tagged me oh he
knew i'd go in his base
i'm gonna go and expect that but first
i've just seen that somebody has built
spongebob squarepants's house
right next to my conduit
unbelievable
oh my goodness this is a pretty good
replication i must admit who lives in a
pineapple under the sea
let's have a look
what is this there's a book is this
meant for me hey neighbor oh
hey neighbor crcr i don't know what it
means hey neighbor i was admiring the
squidward conduit build and realized how
lonely good old squidward was without
his neighbor so i fixed that now all we
need is a rock house for patrick and the
family is together that's so true
it's gary
oh that's oh that's genius
and there's a naughty yeah it's
gary i don't know if you guys have ever
watched
spongebob squarepants but
this is awesome this is ri oh and there
there he is
there he is the man himself
spongebob squarepants
it's rather
uh
it's a bit it's a bit scary i'm actually
going to put the book in here
there we go pop that there
oh my goodness i don't know what i'm
gonna use this for but i'm definitely
keeping this i only really will get rid
of pranks if they don't fit
what i'm doing but since i built
squidward's house he even built it in
this in the right location that is
exactly where spongebob house is
supposed to go now i meant to make the
patrick's house right here but there's a
bit of a problem with the whole
landscaping so i'd have to raise this up
a bit to be able to fit that on and
we're gonna have to do it because we
can't have one well two without the
third
but we need to go and find out if mumbo
jumbo actually tagged us with this
machine that's ridiculous so another
thought if i've been tagged again
i started this game and it's only been
through two people before ending back
with me
how ridiculous is that what a genius way
to tag someone with a machine he he knew
he's a genius he knew i would go for it
and he knew i wouldn't i wouldn't
destroy anything
oh sneaky so this is the little entrance
that i have to mumbo's base because oh
wow this is dangerous oh this is really
dangerous okay so this is the little
like
rickety staircase i've made up to the
other side of his spawner that i said
hello to him in another episode let's
ask him straight up he's facing the
other way afk as normal how do i get his
attention come on dude i'm right here i
have nothing oh wait i could try
throwing stuff at him
are you responsible for this
look at this in my hand was this you
was this you
no
he's a genius
you knew it would get me you knew it
would get me oh unbelievable thanks a
lot mumbo now i've got to come up with
another genius way of tagging somebody
you can ah
no
unbelievable he's gone back afk i can't
tag him now i have to tag somebody else
and i can't tag anybody in my own video
so now i just have to sit here with the
tag i had forgotten that mumbo had it i
thought he would have gotten somebody
else by now
so this is probably a good place to
build
the conference room that i was i was
thinking of so i could build one right
here and make a fairly decent sized path
all the way back to my base so i'm
probably gonna have to do that off
camera but this is a pretty good place
to make it now obviously this is just a
temporary room i'm not actually going to
be using this for anything other than
the conference with with mumbo jumbolio
over there oh man he he played me like a
fiddle he played me like a fiddle i
thought there was something suspicious
about that that slime ball
that slime block it was there was
something off about the whole situation
i'd even been down there thought oh this
looks odd and left and then i came back
and i got tagged by it
all right we're back at the base
so
mumbo was responsible for tagging me
although i was semi-responsible for
tagging myself and all i was doing was
visiting
i think buildstone may be the best thing
that hermitcraft will ever see if mumbo
decides to join forces into a little
group with me and who knows other people
may join over time as well
but it has to be people that we trust
that's the main thing trust is
everything so there's also something i
wanted to do before we go shopping and
before we start actually making progress
on the real base because
look at this look how many furnaces look
how many chests i've got i really need
to get to the point where i have a
proper storage system i need well not to
just have random builds outside my house
i need to really get started but i
wanted to try and make a list of
everything that i want to do
this season
so it is number one is feature every
hermit on the server at least once
number two is start a shop and in
brackets make a profit which
i don't know if that's possible i might
be very late to the game but we'll see
what happens number three is a fairly
simple one that i i imagine i will do
it's
make a proper redstone storage system
number four is take mumbo's mustache
away i sang a pretty funny afk song when
my voice was really rough
and it went something along the lines of
mumbo mumbo afk i'm going to take the
mustache away
you get the idea that there's actually
remixes coming out of that very song so
go and see those if you're interested
i'm not sure how i'm going to do this
yet but trust me we're gonna figure out
a way and number five create a base in
every area
so those are kind of my five bucket list
things that i really want to do of
course i will add to it i may even take
stuff away if i decide that i don't want
to do it much like a real life bucket
list so i thought i would do that so
let's actually head over to the shops
shall we where we can go and purchase a
few things that we desperately
desperately need you know i didn't
really plan for bikini bottom to happen
right outside my base i figured that
this would happen in aqua town but it's
actually kind of funny how these things
work out in the end so i'm mainly
thinking that my base is going to end up
over there but the terrain really
doesn't work with me but i kind of have
to stick to my area because i've got so
many neighbors and i definitely don't
want to tread on any toads so i've been
gathering lots of stone as well so i can
make my own island which may take a very
very long time fortunately we're right
next to the shopping district which is
just around the corner and i know
there's a shulker box shop but i'm not
sure what else
here we are time to do a bit of shopping
looks like there's quite a lot of stuff
going on is that a drowned up there
let's take a look at what we have i'm
looking for the shulker box place
bouche's boutique what's what's it oh
this is a leaf
salesman one diamond per stack that
seems really expensive to me considering
it doesn't take lots to get the
get leaves really it it can take a few
seconds that seems a little bit
expensive
let's go and have a look in here what's
this this is concor presents sad coral
shop
sad coral
no
oh that's horrible
i understand now this place just sells
dead coral plants
oh that's awful in comparison to cub
shop here which sells a live coral i've
actually already purchased a bunch of
stuff from here
and look at this look how beautiful this
coral shop is and he's obviously turned
quite a profit and then look at it from
the outside this is really cool mumbo's
sticky shop so mumbo's already made a
shop i'm guessing selling slime balls
nice
one diamond per stack that seems pretty
reasonable i'll pick up a stack of slime
balls
python shulker box shop yes
oh i thought he was sold out for a
second there undyed eight diamonds each
or two for 15.
hmm let's do two for 15 shall we two
shulker boxes
perfect now that we've got what we came
for we had a look around some of the
shops there let's head on back oh this
is a pretty nice modern house
cubs start a house that's that's a
really good starter house i've got to
say well done cub is he is he killed the
ender drag i need help i need help to
kill the ender dragon
who is the most qualified hermit to help
me kill the ender dragon that's what i
need to know so that i can get my hands
on an elytra so that i can fly around
and be majestic and all that jazz so if
you guys know who who who the person is
to ask to help kill the end dragon with
let me know because that's definitely on
the list not on my bucket list because i
i could go without ever fighting the
ender dragon but it's definitely on my
to-do list
uh home sweet home in green
green's
spongebob squarepants land i don't know
what this is anymore this whatever it is
we're doing here it's not futuristic but
don't worry we will be getting to that
everybody has to make a starter house
and it doesn't really matter that it's
not in theme right now and this is never
going to go don't get me wrong this is
never going to just disappear it's
always going to be here this is our this
is our roots this is our starting town
so it's always going to stay here but
you're right
we do need to build more futuristic
stuff so i've already got a shulker box
that was gifted to me full of terracotta
so i need to fill one up with glass
because we're gonna have to transport a
lot of stuff
so might as well just start
taking everything we're going to need
because this project
is going to take
oh hundreds of hours i think hundreds of
hours which is why i haven't started
until now because i've just been
grinding all of these resources are ones
that i can't farm i've just got to uh
nope that needs to stay that needs to
stay in my inventory i need i need to
grind for them terra cotta i just mined
it in the mazer bio all the glass sand i
had to go get that
so it's been a very long process
right we've got a pretty decent amount
of things now
i'm i'm fairly sure that we can we can
do a lot of things with what we've got
here we will have to get more i mean i
can't fit all of this stuff in but we've
got a lot of it so let's place a few
sea lanterns just to kind of mark out
where we're going
and then we need to make a platform all
the way up to the top
i'm a little bit scared to start this
you know i'm a little bit scared to
start this whole project to be honest
with you it's a massive undertaking
and i definitely don't want to start
something
that i can't finish
that's one of my biggest concerns right
now so we're going to start off with a
very basic
cobblestone platform but first let's
just get set up
we've got a lot to do here
the fact that i've already run out of
cobblestone
making this
rather large platform
is kind of a testament to
how little resources i really have
that's it's a little bit worrying i've
got plenty of valuables don't get me
wrong i'm doing all right on the diamond
front i'm doing very well on the iron
front
but as for everything else
this isn't gonna cut it this isn't gonna
cut it at all
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
start this project
slowly
and smartly we're not gonna rush into
things we will actually do a little bit
of planning
and we'll get this platform made but
before it's getting pretty late and i
really want to propose this whole
buildstone thing to mumbo so let's
quickly go and make this conference room
so so that we can propose this to him
all right we're back at mumbo's base
i really need to make a better system to
get up to here
but we need to make the proposal room no
i'm not gonna marry mumbo but we're
gonna propose buildstone to him
so the first thing that we have to do is
well not only clear this out which i'm
steadily doing but we need to come up
with a design for a logo
because you can't just start a club and
not have a logo that's just bad business
practice so we've really got to come up
with something
i don't know really really us
so this is probably enough space
i've got some obsidian which will work
perfectly well for the eyes
or maybe i could make a coal block but i
don't think i have enough before
and i have some redstone blocks which i
brought with me i wasn't actually going
to do this logo but this sort of came to
me as i was making this hole so let's
make
hmm
we need a two block center
there's an easy mustache easy mumbo
stash
and then
one two
build stone
it looks
really weird
that looks really strange
i'm not entirely sure what that is but
that is buildstone in a nutshell you
know what that really doesn't look very
good that really doesn't look very good
at all
but i just had an even better idea
i could make this like a fan thing if
mumbo says yes
i could propose
that we do a fan competition to design
our logo so that could be really cool
that could be a cool way for you guys to
participate you could tweet it as on
twitter and we could kind of run a
little competition for the buildstone
logo either way i need to quickly create
this conference room and i actually want
to hide it from mumbo so i was actually
going to do a big reveal so give me a
second and let's get this set up as
quickly as possible
okay i think everything is set up of
course
it looks a bit drab in here in my
opinion
so now pretty much all there is left is
to wait for mumbo to stop being afk he's
clearly got back on but he's gone afk
again
unbelievable
i am ready to give
mumbo
the the business deal of the century
i've put on my suit because i've got to
take things seriously okay if i'm gonna
do things i don't do half measures it's
all or nothing okay so let's see if we
can get his attention uh
mumbo he's there he's there can i get
him can i get him on discord for like
two minutes hello hello hello mumbo
what are you doing there
uh well hang on you're looking very
official oh yeah i i've put some i've
put on a new suit because
hold on let me come over to you i mean
i'm i'm i'm a bit confused by your
is this is this just an addition that
you've made to my base
whoa
i've got the business deal of a century
it looks sure looks like it man i'm not
your average door-to-door salesman i i'm
the sort of salesman that lives in your
house and gives you the best deal
possible
you look more like a hotel doorman i
have to say i mean
okay so i got two questions well not
really a question first of all how dare
you i i just got rid of this thing
that was
i i'd say i mean you know what's
hilarious is is that i kind of set this
up
i was like i wonder if this will catch
anything and then i came back to my
computer i was literally just about to
leave the studio and i saw that the
cobblestone had been pulled back by the
slime block and i was like no
sure
and over obviously because you know i'm
i've got super surveillance since you
came along i was recording my afk
session and i managed to catch you yeah
you must have also caught me getting
stuck because i couldn't open this door
and i got i started drowning but that
that might be another moment that you
caught on your security footage
i think i might have done yet how did
you do this how did how does this work
where was the tag
oh the tag was just in this little
dropper down here
so it just it just went straight into
your inventory
of course it did
i mean technically you i mean you can't
get me back because surely this is the
same episode so i'm safe yeah no i can't
no you're right i can't get you anyway
and i have to wait until next episode to
get someone else
yeah oh of course yeah you can't just
re-tag someone yeah of course i gotta go
someone else hilarious the next the next
question i have was did you hear my afk
song that i sang you when you were
standing there
yeah yeah i i've actually had i've i've
heard i've heard a remix of it as well i
believe there's multiple remixes being
worked on i mean i think that might be a
thing that has now become a thing so now
the pressure's on for me to come up with
more songs i don't i'm not a singer
i mean
yeah i don't i
i i hear that you're you've kind of
threatened my mustache is
should i be worried about that no no
it's not a thing it's not a thing
anyway follow me follow me follow me to
okay follow me to my office
yeah let's get away from the sound of
all the zombies in the chat i've got
like the noisiest this is that is not an
official entrance that's not
this is the reception area and uh if you
just come downstairs uh we'll we'll
carry on with the meeting shall we
okay oh wow this is very i like the
gravel wall that's nice yeah all right
so uh take a seat there
yep right i mean these are quite big but
yep yeah so what we're big men we're big
strong men we need big strong chairs
okay so here's my business proposal this
is the big the big thing
so yep i'm new to hermitcraft and it's
pretty safe to say
you're probably my closest friend as
we've done a few videos before you've
even been to my house we recorded cats
that sort of thing you know the standard
things that friends do right
yeah yeah yeah and there are already
some pre-established sort of groups on
the server already operating and doing
their thing the nho and curb and scar
are doing their thing and there are
already little groups forming and i feel
like i want to propose to you a new
group called buildstone
what do you think me and you
buildstone
redstone building
i mean we can change the name if you
want
um no i i like it i like the way you say
it like do you have to say it like this
buildstone exactly it has to be said
like that every time buildstone
builds
okay yeah um no i mean that sounds
interesting yeah that sounds like
something i'd be interested in for sure
and i don't want to get ahead of myself
but i've i've gone and
run the statistics so i've talked with
my analysis and my marketing team which
is me
and i've come up with
a logo
whoa
the build stone build stones i gravel
this is why i need you this is this is
why i need you let me just take care of
this
building
i do the building you do the redstoning
and um i'm not gonna lie this is
probably the worst
logo
ever
it was a bit of a no
it's it's all right it's
build stone i like it i mean it looks
does it come with the torches are these
are these necessities i just needed some
light
okay yeah yeah ignore that
got it well no i like it and i
especially like to reveal that was very
nice
we have like we need like three mission
statements it's to farm
to prank
and to be extra cool like we need some
like we need some goals like we need to
i don't know we just team up i feel like
we are stronger together than apart i
can make big things and then you can
make it useful
oh yeah i see i get yeah that makes yeah
i mean that sounds like something that
i'd be
oh yeah for sure 100
do you have anything in mind to start
off with just out of interest
i i got as far as this proposal i didn't
want to get ahead of myself just in case
you said okay you know what i mean oh
yeah yeah you don't want to invest too
much time i mean you'd already i i can't
i can't imagine how many hours that took
you to build this i mean a little while
it took me a little while so
don't shame me dude
it took me a while i
that was a genuine statement
so the other thing is um i'm not too set
on the logo or the name
so what i've been sort of saying in my
episode is
why don't we open it up a little bit to
the audience and they can submit
some designs for a logo and even a name
and if there's something that sort of
resonates with both of us
we could like take it and then you know
say look at this uh minecrafter one two
three four five six seven eight nine
came up with this
there's a really young username but
what do you think about that build stone
one two three four five six seven eight
nine that's gonna be the new name
[Laughter]
no yeah i like the idea 100 so i guess
yeah we'll have to ask people to submit
things like that on on in the comments
and
and download i think that i think that
was the proposal so far
well i mean oh yeah i definitely sounds
i'm i'm 100 up for it i'm i i can't wait
to get started whatever projects
whatever whatever this group is about
we'll figure it out on the way
exactly
it's already got a few bad signs going
on because i've run out of cobblestone
and i haven't even managed to make the
entire platform i've used
easily 20 odd plus stacks of it and it's
still not quite big enough the problem
is i'm not quite sure how big this
actually needs to be i'm just
guesstimating at the moment and i'm
trying to work out the best location for
it to be because i kind of want a good
amount of distance between that between
that island which is getting pretty
close now i'm pretty sure that belongs
to mumbo
and i want a bit of distance between my
bottle and bikini bottom there as well
so i'm just i'm trying to work it out
but i've already run out of cobblestone
and if i'm running out of cobblestone
that doesn't bode well
for the pitiful amount of resources i've
got there
either way i think that's probably where
we're going to leave the progress for
this base for this episode because it is
going to be a long project it's not
going to be done in a matter of days
it's going to take a really really long
time but i've been thinking about this
in my time while recording this
and
i think i need to get a bit more
creative with how i'm going to tag
someone
so i actually need a bit of equipment
that i don't have
and that
is an elytra i'm going to swoop down and
tag somebody now jevin on the server has
kindly offered to sell me one now i
would go and kill the dragon myself but
i'm not quite there yet i just need an
elytra so i can do it we will kill the
dragon eventually but for now we're just
gonna buy our way to one so we're gonna
head over to jevin's base pick up this
elytra and he's charging me 20 diamonds
for it and i don't know if that's a good
price or a bad price
20 diamonds is a lot so you know that
i'm not buying this lightly
the next question of course is who is
going to be my next target
i feel like it's a really smart thing to
send the tag
to the other side of the map wait a
second what is going on here okay so in
our first episode we passed this boat
and it was just starting to be made oh
it's like a little action sequence oh
that's so cool i love armor stands
they're so neat
right let's head over to his base is
this his base it must be
sebastian
ah oh finally
i should really learn coordinates a bit
better so there's jevin hello
hello
is he afk why is everybody afk
i'm gonna have to sing an afk song for
jevin now jeff and jeff and jeff in afk
won't you come and sell your elytra
today oh he's here hello
so i'm gonna i'm gonna give you an offer
i'm not sure if you want to take it or
not i've got two eligius right um
so for 20 diamonds i'll offer you either
one this one
is already enchanted but it's used it
has mending and breaking on it now what
does mending do exactly
you can repair it with xp
oh okay so like say you go to a spawner
and you just kind of feel the mobs make
sure you put it like in your armor slot
or your shield slot okay and it'll
repair it or i can give you a blank one
and you can enchant it yourself i'm
offering it to you because i've got an
eye trade pass and i can easily get
moving no problem so
[Music]
either way i'm perfectly fine you can
repair this with like five minutes at a
grinder so
uh i'll take i'll take the mending one
i'll take the menu all right perfect
yeah
so um i felt like 20 diamonds was kind
of a good price because on season
4 of hermitcraft we had a shop
and everybody sold their elites for 20
diamonds so i felt like that was a fair
number yeah and here you go
perfect
i i have no i don't actually know if
that's a good price at all i could be
totally you could have you could have
said 60 diamonds and i would have been
like yep there you go
i'm uh i'm not exactly hurting for
diamonds so 20 is perfectly fine with me
so
excellent excellent well the reason
the reason that i have uh
asked for this elytra is because
you know this game that started on the
server
oh tag yeah yeah i'll get
you
oh you got me no i didn't i didn't
because it's still the same episode that
i got tagged so i'm not allowed to tag
anybody but i'm preparing next episode
i'm gonna swoop in on an elytra
and i'm gonna tag somebody so that's why
i'm thinking ahead and i'm grabbing
myself an elytra so that i can swoop
down and catch someone out but it's kind
of circling around the futuristic area
so i'm going to fly to the other side of
the island and swoop down and tag
somebody and it's going to be brilliant
you should uh like stalk your prey
exactly where you're like duck in and
shift in behind blocks and kind of just
like watch them for a while and which is
why i need to get my hands now on a
bunch of fireworks so that i can yeah
i would totally give you fireworks but
gunpowder is like a premium right now it
is a premium right now i don't think
there's anything yeah i i think i have
like three pieces so
yeah there's no as far as i'm aware
there's no farms going on for
general mob drops so anyway thank you
very much you have fueled this game
further
awesome and no problem man have a good
one
what a nice man i won't be uh won't be
tagging him well for one he knows my
plans and he's been part part of it he's
an accomplice now so i'm not going to be
tagging jevin
and i will
probably get this all mended up
he told me that i have to
simply i just i just simply have to get
some xp while i'm holding it and then it
will magically be repaired which is cool
i haven't actually used the elytra in a
survival minecraft world probably ever
so
whoa
this is gonna be good fun this is gonna
be really good fun i'm actually gonna
fly to my base hopefully from up here
okay here we go
wow
why
oh
i thought you just you just double tap
and
okay how do you fly why is it not flying
oh do i have to press control maybe
no oh okay
i did it oh what
so let's do a little runner jump there
we go
and we're flying can we make it all the
way to the base oh this is excellent i
don't really want to be that person that
just flies everywhere because it's super
convenient this elytra i think is just
going to be used for the purpose of tag
for the time being
excellent i do actually need to get my
hands on the rule book because i feel
like i'm going to have to drop that as
well since i'm going to be tagging
somebody new but anyway that's it for
today's episode thank you very much for
watching just to sort of recap what
we've done in this episode
scar has built a pineapple under the sea
over there which was brilliant
and we have started a group called
buildstone or maybe not depending on you
guys
the logo is not confirmed so if you guys
have any better suggestions please tweet
them at me and mumbo jumbo and we will
have a little look and decide
we have started the platform as we have
enough resources to get started
and we have got an elytra where
we are going to tag someone else oh yeah
and mumbo tagged me how dare he thank
you very much for watching everybody i
hope you enjoyed this episode and
goodbye
[Music]